{"tossups":[{"question":"A character in this play swears to give up “taffeta [TAFF-ih-tuh] phrases, silken terms precise” and instead woo with “russet yeas [yays] and honest kersey noes.” Fancy words like “festinately” [FEST-uh-nit-lee] and “epitheton” [uh-PITH-uh-tahn] are used by a courtier who nonetheless ends this play with the simple line “You that way; we this way.” Adherents of the Baconian theory often point to an anagram of this play’s word (*) “honorific·abilitud·ini·tatibus,” which is the longest word in Shakespeare’s corpus. In this play, Costard misunderstands the words “remuneration” and “guerdon” [GER-din] when he is asked to deliver love letters written by Don Armado and Berowne, respectively. The King of Navarre and his companions try to avoid the company of women for three years in, for 10 points, what Shakespeare play with an alliterative title?","formatted_answer":"<b><u>Love’s <\/b><\/u><b><u>Labour’s<\/b><\/u><b><u> Lost<\/b><\/u>","answer":"<b><u>Love’s <\/b><\/u><b><u>Labour’s<\/b><\/u><b><u> Lost<\/b><\/u>","category":"Philosophy","subcategory":"Philosophy","packetNumber":10,"questionNumber":1},{"question":"The Mandarin translation of this English word originated in the Tang dynasty, when a single horizontal stroke in the word tú [“too”] was omitted by the author Lu Yu. This word can synonymously be preceded by either “thunder” or “pounded” to refer to a certain product, because the Chinese words for “thunder” and “pounded” are both pronounced léi [“lay”]. A map published by Quartz in 2018 shows how the Min Nan equivalent of this word generally spread by (*) sea, while the Sinitic [sin-IT-ik] equivalent generally spread by land. Strictly speaking, this word refers only to products of the Camellia sinensis [kuh-MELL-ee-uh see-NEN-sis] plant, and is contrasted with “tisane” [tih-ZAN]. For 10 points, what drink is referred to as “cha” or “chai” in many of the world’s languages?","formatted_answer":"<b><u>tea<\/b><\/u>","answer":"<b><u>tea<\/b><\/u>","category":"Social Science","subcategory":"Social Science","packetNumber":10,"questionNumber":2},{"question":"In Spanish, these characters are called “Pitufos,” inspired by a statue of the Ox of Patufet from Catalan folklore. The original name for these characters, which was coined when their creator forgot the word for “salt,” is pronounced like a German word for “stockings.” A 1972 work parodies a language war via a dispute about how to say “bottle (*) opener” in the language of these characters, in which nouns and verbs are often replaced with the name for these characters. These characters, who typically have descriptive names like “Greedy,” “Brainy,” and “Clumsy,” are called “Schtroumpfs” [SH’TROOMPF] in the original language. For 10 points, name these diminutive blue creatures from a Belgian comic series.","formatted_answer":"the <b><u>Smurf<\/b><\/u>s [or de <b><u>Smurf<\/b><\/u>en; accept les <b><u>Schtroumpf<\/b><\/u>s before “Schtroumpfs”]","answer":"the <b><u>Smurf<\/b><\/u>s [or de <b><u>Smurf<\/b><\/u>en; accept les <b><u>Schtroumpf<\/b><\/u>s before “Schtroumpfs”]","category":"Social Science","subcategory":"Social Science","packetNumber":10,"questionNumber":3},{"question":"John Ashbery and James Schuyler [skyler] ended their novel A Nest of Ninnies with an obscure word for one of these things so that readers would have to open a dictionary upon closing the novel. In The English Patient, Almásy’s [ALL-mah-shee’s] copy of Herodotus lists words for these phenomena such as africo [AH-free-koh], khamsin [hahm-SEEN], and (*) ghibli [GEE-blee]. Other terms for local examples of these things are “Fremantle Doctor” in Australia, foehn [fain] in the Alps, and simoom [see-MOOM] in much of the Arab world. One of these things whose name means “masterly” in Languedoc [long-DOCK] is called “mistral” [mis-TRAWL]. Some Greeks distinguished eight principal examples of these things with names like Eurus [YOO-riss], Notos [NOH-tohss], and Zephyrus [ZEF-uh-riss]. For 10 points, name these weather phenomena, one of which in California is called “Santa Ana.”","formatted_answer":"<b><u>wind<\/b><\/u>s [prompt on <u>weather<\/u> phenomena before “weather”]","answer":"<b><u>wind<\/b><\/u>s [prompt on weather phenomena before “weather”]","category":"Geography","subcategory":"Geography","packetNumber":10,"questionNumber":4},{"question":"This author was responsible for the first recorded use of the word “bisexual,” though it referred to androgyny rather than a sexual orientation. This author coined the word “esemplastic” to describe the unifying power of the imagination. This writer defined poetry as “the best words in the best order.” This author and Robert Southey used the word (*) “pantisocracy” for their proposed egalitarian utopia. This author coined the phrase “suspension of disbelief” in an 1817 combination of autobiography, philosophy and literary criticism titled Biographia Literaria. A poem by this author introduced the phrase “pleasure dome.” For 10 points, name this poet who inspired the idiom “albatross around one’s neck” with his Rime of the Ancient Mariner.","formatted_answer":"Samuel Taylor <b><u>Coleridge<\/b><\/u>  Note to moderator: Be sure to pronounce the first vowel in zurdo clearly, so players do not confuse it with sordo, the Spanish word for “deaf.”","answer":"Samuel Taylor <b><u>Coleridge<\/b><\/u>  Note to moderator: Be sure to pronounce the first vowel in zurdo clearly, so players do not confuse it with sordo, the Spanish word for “deaf.”","category":"Literature","subcategory":"British Literature","packetNumber":10,"questionNumber":5},{"question":"In Australian slang, these people can be called “mollydookers.” The last name “Mancini” comes from an Italian word for these people. A hyphenated British adjective starting with the word “cack,” meaning “excrement,” can refer to this specific type of person. A Russian word for these people can also refer to a skilled craftsman, in reference to a story by Nikolai (*) Leskov about a man who makes a steel flea. In Spanish, these people are described by the word zurdo [SOOR-doh], which is the opposite of diestro [DYESS-troh]. The widespread negative associations with these people are illustrated by the negative meanings of the French word gauche [gohsh] and the English word “sinister.” For 10 points, name these people who are sometimes called “southpaws.”","formatted_answer":"<b><u>left-handed<\/b><\/u> people [or <b><u>leftie<\/b><\/u>s; accept <b><u>southpaw<\/b><\/u>s before “southpaws”; prompt on <u>clumsy<\/u> or <u>inept<\/u> or other synonyms by asking “What more specific type of person does that word refer to?”, because many of the terms clued can also refer metaphorically to clumsy people]","answer":"<b><u>left-handed<\/b><\/u> people [or <b><u>leftie<\/b><\/u>s; accept <b><u>southpaw<\/b><\/u>s before “southpaws”; prompt on clumsy or inept or other synonyms by asking “What more specific type of person does that word refer to?”, because many of the terms clued can also refer metaphorically to clumsy people]","category":"Literature","subcategory":"American Literature","packetNumber":10,"questionNumber":6},{"question":"A bilingual text by this author uses the Greek word eusebeia [ay-oo-SAY-bay-ah] and the Aramaic word qsyt [kuh-SEET], meaning “truth,” for the same concept. One argument for the influence of Achaemenid [uh-KEE-muh-nid] writings on this author’s works is this author’s use of the word dipi [dippy] in texts written in the Kharosthi [kah-rohsh-TEE] script and lipi [lippy] in other texts. The (*) Brahmi [BRAH-mee] numerals, the predecessors of modern Arabic numerals, are first attested in this person’s writings. This person referred to himself as “Devanampiya” [day-vuh-num-pee-ah], meaning “beloved of the gods,” in 3rd-century BCE inscriptions that mostly used the Prakrit [PRAH-krit] language to lay out his view of dharma [DAR-muh]. Many rock and pillar edicts were promulgated by, for 10 points, what Mauryan [MOR-yin] emperor who converted to Buddhism?","formatted_answer":"<b><u>Ashoka<\/b><\/u> the Great [accept <b><u>Priyadasi<\/b><\/u>; accept <b><u>Piyadasi<\/b><\/u>; prompt on <u>Devanampiya<\/u> or <u>Devanampriya<\/u> before “Devanampiya”] (Eusebeia and qsyt are Ashoka’s translations of dharma.)","answer":"<b><u>Ashoka<\/b><\/u> the Great [accept <b><u>Priyadasi<\/b><\/u>; accept <b><u>Piyadasi<\/b><\/u>; prompt on Devanampiya or Devanampriya before “Devanampiya”] (Eusebeia and qsyt are Ashoka’s translations of dharma.)","category":"History","subcategory":"World History","packetNumber":10,"questionNumber":7},{"question":"This word was cryptically hidden in the inner spine of the CD release of Weezer’s Green Album. The speaker says “my name is [this word], my sign is [this word], my number is [this word]” in the lead single from the 2016 album Thank You by Meghan Trainor. Leonard Maltin’s review of a 1948 musical starring Veronica Lake consists (*) only of this word. An iconic use of this word was followed by nine months of silence and then the question “how do i get cowboy paint off a dog.” The French translation of this word is the only word spoken in Mel Brooks’s Silent Movie. Dril’s first tweet consists only of this word. Betteridge’s law states that any headline that ends in a question mark can be answered with, for 10 points, what negative word?","formatted_answer":"<b><u>no<\/b><\/u> (Maltin’s review was for the film Isn’t It Romantic?)","answer":"<b><u>no<\/b><\/u> (Maltin’s review was for the film Isn’t It Romantic?)","category":"Fine Arts","subcategory":"Visual Fine Arts","packetNumber":10,"questionNumber":8},{"question":"In 2018, researchers at the Max Planck Institute created a game whose users had to communicate these things using symbols instead of words. Words for these things were called “foolish” by a Boston professor who instead characterized these things using three properties, including one called “value.” Berlin and Kay theorized that there are (*) eleven basic categories of words for these things that cultures tend to adopt in a specific order. Midori [mee-doh-ree] is a relatively recently adopted Japanese word for one of these things. A mismatch between these things and the words for these things causes a delay in processing in the classic version of the Stroop effect. For 10 points, name these things described by the words “puce” [pooce], “chartreuse” [shar-TROOZ], and “indigo.”","formatted_answer":"<b><u>color<\/b><\/u>s [accept The <b><u>Color<\/b><\/u> Game] (The professor was Albert Munsell, the developer of the Munsell color system.)","answer":"<b><u>color<\/b><\/u>s [accept The <b><u>Color<\/b><\/u> Game] (The professor was Albert Munsell, the developer of the Munsell color system.)","category":"Literature","subcategory":"Other Literature","packetNumber":10,"questionNumber":9},{"question":"This language’s system of tense, aspect, and mood is called “screeve.” In this language, deda [deh-dah] means “mother” and mama [mah-mah] means “father.” The letter las [loss] from this language’s 33-letter Mkhedruli [m’hed-roo-lee] script is often used to represent a fist in emoticons. Because this language’s word mepe [meh-peh] is gender-neutral, a queen who ruled from 1184 to 1213 is often referred to as a (*) “king.” This language’s own name for its home country means “land of Kartvelians.” Though the modern form of this language uses vepkhvi [vep-h’vee] to mean “tiger,” the title of its national epic is typically translated as The Knight in the Panther’s Skin. Suffixes meaning “son” and “child,” -dze [dzeh] and -shvili [shvee-lee], are common ends for surnames in this language. For 10 points, name this language spoken in Tbilisi [tuh-bih-LEE-see].","formatted_answer":"<b><u>Georgian<\/b><\/u> [or <b><u>kartuli<\/b><\/u> ena]","answer":"<b><u>Georgian<\/b><\/u> [or <b><u>kartuli<\/b><\/u> ena]","category":"Social Science","subcategory":"Social Science","packetNumber":10,"questionNumber":10},{"question":"An adjective used to describe these objects is defined by Tracy Lord after Dexter gives her a wedding present in The Philadelphia Story. The phrase “by and large” originally referred to two different ways these objects can be used. Words for parts of these objects include “orlop,” “taffrail,” and “binnacle.” According to a popular folk etymology, the word (*) “posh” is an acronym referring to the parts of these objects. When these objects are easily maneuvered, they are said to be “yar.” Adverbs used to describe positions on these objects include “abeam” and “abaft.” The phrase “I like the cut of your jib” refers metaphorically to part of one of these objects. For 10 points, name these vehicles whose parts include hulls and keels.","formatted_answer":"<b><u>boat<\/b><\/u>s [or <b><u>ship<\/b><\/u>s; or <b><u>vessel<\/b><\/u>s; or <b><u>watercraft<\/b><\/u>; accept <b><u>sailboat<\/b><\/u>s; accept <b><u>cruise ship<\/b><\/u>s; accept <b><u>sail<\/b><\/u>s before “orlop”]","answer":"<b><u>boat<\/b><\/u>s [or <b><u>ship<\/b><\/u>s; or <b><u>vessel<\/b><\/u>s; or <b><u>watercraft<\/b><\/u>; accept <b><u>sailboat<\/b><\/u>s; accept <b><u>cruise ship<\/b><\/u>s; accept <b><u>sail<\/b><\/u>s before “orlop”]","category":"Science","subcategory":"Other Science","packetNumber":10,"questionNumber":11},{"question":"According to a 9th-century text, this phrase makes Satan turn as small as a fly, while the phrase “cursed Satan” simply makes him stronger. In some contexts, this phrase is followed by between one and five letters known as the “mysterious letters.” The number 786 is spiritually significant because the letters of this phrase add up to 786 in a standard system of numerology. Several (*) hadith [hah-DEETH] recommend reciting this phrase before eating or drinking, and reciting it before sexual intercourse is also recommended. The ninth sura [SOO-rah] is the only chapter of the Qur’an [kur-AHN] that doesn’t start with this phrase. For 10 points, name this Arabic phrase meaning “in the name of God, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful.”","formatted_answer":"<b><u>Bismillah<\/b><\/u> [or <b><u>Basmala<\/b><\/u>; or <b><u>Tasmiyah<\/b><\/u>; or <b><u>bi-<\/b><\/u><b><u>smi<\/b><\/u> <b><u>llāhi<\/b><\/u><b><u> r-<\/b><\/u><b><u>raḥmāni<\/b><\/u><b><u> r-<\/b><\/u><b><u>raḥīm<\/b><\/u>]","answer":"<b><u>Bismillah<\/b><\/u> [or <b><u>Basmala<\/b><\/u>; or <b><u>Tasmiyah<\/b><\/u>; or <b><u>bi-<\/b><\/u><b><u>smi<\/b><\/u> <b><u>llāhi<\/b><\/u><b><u> r-<\/b><\/u><b><u>raḥmāni<\/b><\/u><b><u> r-<\/b><\/u><b><u>raḥīm<\/b><\/u>]","category":"Religion","subcategory":"Religion","packetNumber":10,"questionNumber":12},{"question":"This director included the prediction “soon everyone will need an interpreter to understand the words coming out of their mouths” in a film that prominently features this director’s dog Roxy. This director used a pun on the words “analysis” and “anal” in a scene in which a woman describes a sexual experience at great length. In a film by this director, a pen changes a word meaning “art” to a word meaning “death” before the protagonist ties (*) dynamite to his head and blows himself up. This director’s 1960s films feature extensive use of red, white, and blue intertitles. In the much-debated last line of dialogue in a film by this director, Patricia asks what the word dégueulasse [day-guh-LASS] means while Michel is dying, having been shot by the police. For 10 points, name this French New Wave director of Breathless.","formatted_answer":"Jean-Luc <b><u>Godard<\/b><\/u>","answer":"Jean-Luc <b><u>Godard<\/b><\/u>","category":"Fine Arts","subcategory":"Other Fine Arts","packetNumber":10,"questionNumber":13},{"question":"In this country, the term “shrub” refers to an English word that is mispronounced due to inference from this country’s indigenous languages. An actor from this country used the Kalenjin language and another language from this country to voice the Return of the Jedi character Nien Nunb [NYE-en NUN-buh]. This country is named for a place whose name means “the one with the ostrich” because of its patches of (*) white. The language of this African country’s largest ethnic group uses a Latin alphabet that includes both an “i” with a tilde and a “u” with a tilde. An author from this country wrote the book Decolonising the Mind, which explains his decision to write in Kikuyu [gay-koh-yoh] instead of English. Ngũgĩ wa Thiong’o [n’goh-gay wah thee-ong-oh] is from, for 10 points, what country where Mau Mau rebels opposed British colonists?","formatted_answer":"Republic of <b><u>Kenya<\/b><\/u> [or Jamhuri ya <b><u>Kenya<\/b><\/u>]","answer":"Republic of <b><u>Kenya<\/b><\/u> [or Jamhuri ya <b><u>Kenya<\/b><\/u>]","category":"History","subcategory":"World History","packetNumber":10,"questionNumber":14},{"question":"A 1991 essay arguing that a practice-based definition of this noun is a “bridge” that is “not built on anyone’s back” is titled “From Practice to Theory.” Emi Koyama is one of many people who have criticized the definition of this word used by the organizers of a music festival called Michfest [MISH-fest] for short. This word’s plural describes a “social collective,” according to an Iris Marion Young essay that describes a related concept as “seriality.” Madison (*) Cawthorn tried to define this word after telling Nancy Pelosi “science isn’t Burger King, you can’t just have it your way.” Ketanji Brown Jackson responded “I’m not a biologist” when Marsha Blackburn asked her to define this word. For 10 points, name this word that many transphobes claim can simply be defined as “adult human female.”","formatted_answer":"<b><u>woman<\/b><\/u> [or <b><u>women<\/b><\/u>; accept <b><u>womyn<\/b><\/u>] (“From Practice to Theory” is by Catharine MacKinnon. Michfest is short for the Michigan Womyn’s Music Festival, which admitted only what it called “womyn-born womyn.”)","answer":"<b><u>woman<\/b><\/u> [or <b><u>women<\/b><\/u>; accept <b><u>womyn<\/b><\/u>] (“From Practice to Theory” is by Catharine MacKinnon. Michfest is short for the Michigan Womyn’s Music Festival, which admitted only what it called “womyn-born womyn.”)","category":"Philosophy","subcategory":"Philosophy","packetNumber":10,"questionNumber":15},{"question":"This person coined the phrase “skunked term” for a word that is difficult to use because it is in the middle of a semantic transition. An essay about this person always renders the word “snoot” in all caps. This person, who has written two books with Antonin Scalia, is the current editor-in-chief of Black’s Law Dictionary. This person is called a genius for synthesizing descriptivism and prescriptivism in (*) David Foster Wallace’s essay “Authority and American Usage.” Data on usage based on Google Ngrams is included in the most recent edition of this author’s thousand-page magnum opus. For 10 points, name this lexicographer whose Modern English Usage was originally published in 1998 as A Dictionary of Modern American Usage.","formatted_answer":"Bryan (Andrew) <b><u>Garner<\/b><\/u>","answer":"Bryan (Andrew) <b><u>Garner<\/b><\/u>","category":"Philosophy","subcategory":"Philosophy","packetNumber":10,"questionNumber":16},{"question":"A book that defines this philosophy as “enlightened false consciousness” uses two different spellings of this philosophy’s name to distinguish its “cheeky” and non-cheeky incarnations. Members of this school used a word meaning “mist” or “smoke” to describe vanity or mental confusion; that word is used in the description of an ideal state written by a member of this school named (*) Crates [KRAH-tess] of Thebes. The name of this school may reference a temple of Heracles where Antisthenes [an-TISS-thuh-neez] lectured. A member of this school supposedly produced a plucked chicken in response to Plato’s definition of man as a “featherless biped.” The Greek word for “doglike” is the origin of the name of, for 10 points, what philosophical school that included Diogenes [dye-AH-juh-neez]?","formatted_answer":"<b><u>Cynic<\/b><\/u>ism (The book in the first clue is Peter Sloterdijk’s Critique of Cynical Reason.)","answer":"<b><u>Cynic<\/b><\/u>ism (The book in the first clue is Peter Sloterdijk’s Critique of Cynical Reason.)","category":"Philosophy","subcategory":"Philosophy","packetNumber":10,"questionNumber":17},{"question":"In Polish, one of these phrases about a beetle buzzing in the reeds derives from a poem by Jan Brzechwa [B’ZHEK-fah]. According to a popular folk etymology, one of the most famous of these phrases was inspired by the paleontologist Mary Anning. A novel titled for one of these phrases follows characters like the photographer Códac [KOH-dahk] and the writer (*) Bustrófedon [boo-STROH-fay-dohn]. A phrase of this type is the basis for a song that Don Lockwood sings while being coached in Singin’ in the Rain. A novel by Guillermo Cabrera Infante is titled for one of these phrases in Spanish about “three sad tigers.” The sign language equivalents of these phrases are called “finger fumblers.” For 10 points, name these phrases that include “she sells seashells by the seashore.”","formatted_answer":"<b><u>tongue-twister<\/b><\/u>s","answer":"<b><u>tongue-twister<\/b><\/u>s","category":"Literature","subcategory":"World Literature","packetNumber":10,"questionNumber":18},{"question":"In the introduction to a novel, this author declared that “the artist deals in what cannot be said in words” and “the novelist says in words what cannot be said in words.” Words exuded by ants are translated by “therolinguists” in this writer’s story “The Author of the Acacia Seeds.” In a story by this author, the wizard Festin sacrifices himself and defeats the evil wizard Voll by uttering the “word of unbinding.” This author coined the word (*) “ansible” for a device capable of near-instantaneous communication. The novella The Word for World Is Forest is part of this author’s Hainish Cycle. Seeing a road sign for Salem, Oregon in a mirror inspired this author to name a utopian city “Omelas.” For 10 points, name this author of sci-fi novels like The Dispossessed and The Left Hand of Darkness.","formatted_answer":"Ursula K. <b><u>Le <\/b><\/u><b><u>Guin<\/b><\/u> [or Ursula Kroeber <b><u>Le <\/b><\/u><b><u>Guin<\/b><\/u>]","answer":"Ursula K. <b><u>Le <\/b><\/u><b><u>Guin<\/b><\/u> [or Ursula Kroeber <b><u>Le <\/b><\/u><b><u>Guin<\/b><\/u>]","category":"Literature","subcategory":"American Literature","packetNumber":10,"questionNumber":19},{"question":"A problem caused by this word was first identified in ALGOL 60 and is a classic example of a shift-reduce conflict in an LR parser. That problem, in which this word is said to be “dangling,” results in certain nested statements being rendered ambiguous. In Haskell, unlike in most languages, this word is compulsory in certain control structures unless guards are used instead. In many languages, this word can be used before (*) “if” to introduce an expression that will be executed only if it evaluates to true and the previous expression evaluates to false. This optional word commonly introduces a branch that is immediately followed by the words “end if.” For 10 points, name this word that can follow “if” and “then” in a conditional construct.","formatted_answer":"<b><u>else<\/b><\/u> [accept dangling <b><u>else<\/b><\/u>]","answer":"<b><u>else<\/b><\/u> [accept dangling <b><u>else<\/b><\/u>]","category":"Science","subcategory":"Other Science","packetNumber":10,"questionNumber":20}],"bonuses":[]}
